Shivan Jameel Othman

Duhok Governorate, Iraq



shvan.jameel93@gmail.com



+964 750 454 4935



linkedin.com/in/shivanjameel

Summary

I am an energetic, ambitious person who has developed a mature and responsible approach to any task that I undertake, or situation that I am presented with. As a graduate with 4 years' worth of experience in IT and management, I am excellent at working with others to achieve a certain objective on time and with excellence.

Experience

Head Of Department - Lecturer

Ararat Private Technical Institute

Oct 2021 - Feb 2022

- Collaborated with a team of 10 lecturers on lesson planning, class, exam writing, and adjust course curriculums.
- Present lectures on a weekly basis alongside managing the department.
- Facilitate communication between students and lecturers.
- workshops, lectures, and training sessions, Lecturing Theoretical lectures according to course of (Computer Skills, and Computer Applications) for the first stage.

Data Entry Specialist

Barzani Charity Foundation

Apr 2021 - Oct 2021

- Inserting orphans' data by entering the existing text and digital information from the source documents Inserting bank account for orphans and the permanent follow-up to open a new account.
- Collecting information, verifying its accuracy, and sorting it according to priorities to prepare the source data for computer entry.
- Review data, correct any inconsistency, and investigate the output.
- Monitoring and Evaluation
- Search and get more information about incomplete documents.
- Creating reports, storing completed works on the specific site, and performing backup operations, especially for orphans' annual reports. Scan documents and print files.

IT Officer Notary public

ICT Company

May 2020 - Jan 2021

Resolve problems associated with application software and operating systems; determine the source of problems.

- Configure, maintain, troubleshoot and support computer, laptops, printers.
- Install and support desktop & laptop PCs, tablets and mobile hardware and software.
- Ensure desktop computers interconnect with diverse systems including associated validation
- All software programs are up to date and activate Microsoft office products and operating systems- Ensure that all computers (hardware and software), networks, multifunctional printers, and any other IT devices are set up and regularly maintained correctly.

Education

Eastern Mediterranean University

Master's degree, Computer Engineering 2016 - 2018

Nawroz University

Bachelor's degree, computer and IT 2011 – 2015

Licenses & Certifications

TOEFL IBT - ETS

EF SET Certificate - EF Standard English Test (EF SET)

General English program - Arizona State University

English for Career Development - University of Pennsylvania

English for Career Development Self-Paced MOOC 2023 - U.S. Department of State

Human Rights, International Humanitarian Law, Community Based Protection

(CBP) and Crisis Management - SWEDO - The Swedish Development Aid Organization

Skills

Data Processing, Humanitarian, Software Testing, Information Technology, Office 365, Data Entry - Data Collection, Multitasking, Typing, Management Information Systems (MIS), MS Office, Communication

LANGUAGES

KURDISH: Native

ENGLISH: Advance

ARABIC: Advance